I talked to a billionaire mentor yesterday, and he told me this story of a study that was just done on Princeton seminary students.
They're studying Good Samaritanism.
And so they had them give this speech at the auditorium, which was across campus, and they separated seminary students into three groups.
And before they started the experiment, they said, hey, how good of a person are you?
How likely are you to be a Good Samaritan?
They had them rate themselves.
Then they had them walk to the auditorium and give their presentation.
So on the way to the auditorium, they had a hallway that was so narrow that no two people could really like go side to side.
And so they had somebody positioned right in the middle of the hallway that had clearly fallen and needed help.
What was interesting is that the three groups they separated into group one, people who were 10 minutes early, group two, people who were on time to their speech, and group three, people who were 10 minutes late.
Do you want to know what predicted whether they were going to stop their tardiness or whether they said they were a good person?
Well, it turns out what they rated themselves as a good person had absolutely nothing to do with whether they actually stopped.
The thing that did was how late they were.
63% of people who were 10 minutes early stopped while there's only 10% did when they were late.
It is significantly harder to be kind when you do not have capacity.
This is why it is ethical for many people at a current stage in life to take care of yourself so that you have the capacity to help others.
And so despite the fact that you may perceive yourself as virtuous because you do not have the ability to provide for other people,
it makes sense and is ethical to be prosperous that you should seek out abundance so that you can have spillover and help other people.